THE WARNING GOD GAVE TB JOSHUA!!!
Thank you!
Good morning!
You may be seated, thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
There is a common thing today that is really giving me so much concern:
You see people talking about their situation
and times without number we have preached about this,
that situations are not your enemy but friend.
People talk so much about their situation instead of talking about the Redeemer, Jesus Christ.
They say, "Situation, situation" - everywhere.
In my country Nigeria; they are expecting elections in a few days.
You can see many people...
Instead of talking about your Redeemer, you are talking about your challenges, your situation.
Tell your neighbour:
You talk about your situation so much instead of your Redeemer.
Hallelujah.
Situation is not an enemy to a Christian.
Situations are meant to improve us, not impair us.
As a Christian, our struggles make us stronger.
It is meant to improve us.
Our situation is not like others’, unless you are not a believer.
When you see someone saying, "I have headache", and you too have headache,
you are a Christian, and that person is not -
your headache is not like his headache.
Your headache is meant to improve you, to strengthen your desire and your determination.
- For who?
- God.
They say, "Ah, this problem of this country is too much. What has happened?"
No.
Your problem is not like others’.
They are not meant to kill you or destroy you
but to strengthen your desire,
to strengthen your character.
Let's quickly look at John 16 - the last verse there, 33.
“I have told you these things, so that in me you may have peace.
In this world you will have trouble. But take heart! I have overcome the world.”
When you look at the Book of Luke 22:32:
“But I have prayed for you, Simon, that your faith may not fail…”
That is to tell you that there will always be an issue that will challenge our faith.
A true Christian, a true believer is tested.
The Book of John 16 shows that we are not in Heaven.
Something must punch us and test our faith.
It could be hardship, sickness, setback or nightmares – just name it.
Something must punch, poke and test your faith.
We are not in Heaven; we are in the world but we are not part of them.
Why are you so concerned about your situation instead of your Redeemer, Healer, Saviour?
There will always be an issue that will challenge your faith.
This is the beauty in our journey to eternal life,
the beauty in our journey with Christ Jesus.
What you see as foolish is beauty; it makes our journey valuable.
If not the situations I have gone through in the past, do you think I would be in the position I am today?
This is the beauty in our journey to eternal life,
the beauty in our journey with Christ Jesus.
That hardship, trouble, name-calling, foolish thing, sickness -
as a Christian - beauty.
Don’t forget, Jesus does not maintain what He does not form.
That is why you have to carry Him along.
Carry Him along in your marriage, business.
He does not maintain what He does not form.
Does He form your marriage?
Does He form your business?
And you are asking Him to maintain it.
You are calling Him to maintain your life, marriage...
Does He actually form it?
We misjudge ourselves when we are in circumstances and situations such as failure.
"Why me? I'm a Christian. Why all this failure, trouble?
Is it a result of my going to church? Is it a result of stopping smoking?
Is it a result of stopping going to parties, night clubs? Why? Why me?"
You begin to look at Jesus in a bad light.
A TRUE CHRISTIAN IS TESTED
A man can be poor and yet be a friend of Jesus.
A man can be sick in body and yet be a candidate of Heaven.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We cannot separate warfare from salvation.
Tell your neighbour.
Again.
We cannot separate warfare from salvation.
True salvation will put us into direct conflict with satan.
All these salvations you are talking about are fake.
You say you are saved.
What do you mean by being saved?
You are not saved; that is why you are like this, you are what you are.
You are not saved yet.
Salvation is not on the street.
You say you are saved - who told you?
You are still a religious person.
You talk more of your situation instead of your Redeemer.
True salvation will put you into direct conflict with satan.
What do I mean?
A true Christian is tested by his ability to face circumstances and situations.
Tell your neighbour.
Little circumstances - you run to witch doctor, just because of challenges.
From one church to another.
Open your calendar and number the churches you have attended in searching for Jesus Christ,
and yet, you are still looking for Jesus.
Can you name how many times you have been baptized?
And yet, you are searching for the Holy Ghost.
And just one baptism leads to Holy Ghost.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The true Christian, believer, true you, is tested by his ability to face circumstances and situations.
Lack of trial, temptation...
It is impossible to worship God without challenges.
Where are we going, because this is the season of challenges?
You talk more of your challenges than your Redeemer.
This is why I am here today to tell you, my brothers and sisters:
Jesus does not maintain what He does not form.
I am just here to remind you what you know already.
The business is not going well; that is why you are here today? You are wasting your time.
You should be here for the salvation of your soul.
It is that salvation that can help you maintain your miracle.
Think about maintenance.
What is maintenance?
Since morning you have been here,
you have been observing all what has been going on...
Look at the church.
What do you see there - empty seats.
Look at there - empty seats.
But million people want to enter here.
It is not the number of people that enter here that matters but the souls that are being saved.
Yes, millions want to enter.
I learned this from the Apostles of the old.
How many of them had a church?
They evangelized all over.
We are looking for crowds today, but what of the soul?
How many of us have prepared to come here today?
Even half of the people inside the church are not prepared to come here.
Maybe after sitting down, after a while they begin to think of...
"I thought I can get a woman here today. I thought I can get an MD here today.
I thought I can get some connection here. I don't know."
There are many messengers of satan here; they captured them.
You have to be very careful - those who are here for the salvation of soul.
We are not here because of your money or offering.
If we were here because of offering, that place would not be empty.
We are not here because of offerings; we are here because of the souls!
I was in revelation of recent and the Lord showed me,
"Look, Joshua, see what you are doing."
I looked at it - "Be careful!"
I said, "Yes, Sir".
"Be careful."
What should I be careful about?
"Remember, membership is not your strength.
Look for the souls. Save the soul.
Don't have the church here because of money, putting the crowd together because of money."
I said, "Yes, Sir".
So the grace we are asking for now,
this is one of the reasons why you have not been seeing me coming out.
From that entrance, by the time you enter, from there they can ask you to go;
not people but the Spirit of God will send you back.
That is the standard of church.
Read your Bible.
You enter the Apostolic ministry in the New Testament and the Old Testament -
by the time you enter, there you will be screened by the Spirit of God.
"There go, come, go, come..."
If your salvation is not yet now, from the gate, instead of people screening you -
this is what I'm asking grace for now -
not to open the gate for everyone to enter, but from the gate you will find yourself being delivered.
From there, back home.
- "No, no, I'm going."
- "Why are you not entering? What happened?"
- "I'm going."
- "Ok."
That is it.
Remember, this is an Apostolic ministry.
What is an Apostolic ministry?
The foundation of the Church is the Holy Ghost
and if it is the Holy Ghost, it is your heart that should worship, not your body.
But today bodies worship in the church – no longer the hearts of people.
Faith is of man’s heart, not of man’s body.
It is our body now that worships.
Look at me, I'm standing - what can you see?
Appearance, camouflage you are looking at, but the real person is inside
you can only see with your heart.
Can you see anything apart from this camouflage?
These are the kind of persons we are today.
This is why you will be looking at the man that is talking - "Is it of God?"
When a seed is planted, we don't know what it is.
But the same seed has germinated, and we don't know what it is, and the same tree has borne fruit.
The same fruit is what we are eating now - you see three Apostles - we are eating their fruit.
The tree has germinated and is bearing fruit now - the same fruit.
They are the ones that have been walking since morning and you have seen.
Yet, you don't know the seed.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TT Robert Begier 22/02/2019
RV: Mel Flowers 22/02/2019